<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>allyson kate</title>
    <description>Allyson Wakeman&#39;s Website Online</description>
    <link>https://allysonkate.github.io//</link>
    <atom:link href="https://allysonkate.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>The Second City</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/SC_2014_logo_blk.png&quot; alt=&quot;SC Logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In January of 2014, I was hired at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.secondcity.com/&quot;&gt;The Second City&lt;/a&gt;, a world-renowned comedy club, theatre and school of improvisation,  as design intern. Since then, I have grown from intern to Jr. Designer, and Jr Designer to Designer on a team of 5.  As part of a small design team in a multi-fasicted company, I’ve been able to have a hand in almost every department across the globe and cater my position to areas I’ve seen need, potential, and had personal interest. A few of my favorite projects and products are discussed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/SC_SCTV.png&quot; alt=&quot;SCTV&quot; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;sctv.com&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our theater in Toronto expressed the need for a product that showed off SCTV to potential clients interested in our SCTV archive. The goal was to showcase the history of SCTV Network, the actors, and the legacy the show and actors have left behind. I served as the lead creative director for the project and and sole designer and developer. Using an existing Wordpress theme, I reworked the site with custom code to better fit the needs of the client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/SC_Main.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Second City&quot; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;secondcity.com&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a grew within the company, I showed interest in the redesign of the website on Wordpress, a project that had been contracted out before I was hired. I saw a great need for project management, UX knowledge, and communication within our company regarding this redesign. Along with the VP of New Media at The Second City, I became a point person for the project. I started researching client needs, wireframing pages, helping with quality control &amp;amp; page speed, and discussing our user experience needs and information architecture with the contractor. Featured above are a few of the pages I hand in redesigning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/SC_Network.png&quot; alt=&quot;Second City Network&quot; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Second City Network&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another project I expressed early interest in was our YouTube channel, SecondCityNetwork. I helped rebrand the channel and create a variety of end cards to increase audience retention and engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 01:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://allysonkate.github.io//work/2016/02/15/the-second-city/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://allysonkate.github.io//work/2016/02/15/the-second-city/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SND Makes Invitational</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/SND_Desktop.png&quot; alt=&quot;SND I Want In Desktop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you get invited to a prototyping event focusing on problems facing modern media companies and news organizations… you throw yourself at it. When I got the invitation from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/chriscoyier/&quot;&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt;, co-founder of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codepen.io/&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;, I was instantly interested in the Society of News Design and the awesome premise of this event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt; “How might we grow community around games, the artists who make them, the fans that love them?” &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was teamed up with Chris; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/charlie_l_hall/&quot;&gt;Charlie&lt;/a&gt;, a features writer at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.polygon.com/&quot;&gt;Polygon&lt;/a&gt;; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/nicolezhu/&quot;&gt;Nicole&lt;/a&gt;, a fellow at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.knightlab.northwestern.edu/&quot;&gt;NU Knight Lab&lt;/a&gt;. We set out to create a marketplace to bridge the gap between playtesters and potential playtesters. Being one of the members of the team who was more familiar with the gaming community, I focused on the user interviews and UI over the course of the weekend.  One of the things that makes SNDMakes so great is that it’s not a competition, so teams are able to focus more on answering what the problem is, why it’s worth solving, and for whom. Our product? I Want In.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Players are hungry for new experiences, and developers are starved for playtesters — especially in the early stages of design. ‘I Want In’ presents developers with a community of players who are given the opportunity to identify their interest in a given game project, and ask a developer to be included in a playtest cycle. Developers can select who they’re letting into their tests, and can reward the best playtesters with badges and other tokens - including retail game codes - to raise their profile in the community making them more likely to be included in other projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The most incredible part of the weekend for me was our user research process. Thanks to Charlie’s intimate network of game developers, we were able to interview several developers all over the world and really pinpoint what our goals, like sourcing playtesters with a diverse experience level, and focus on the hurdles our platform had to overcome, such as the benefit of in-person playtesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;“I want in” from Team Printer&amp;#39;s Row &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/SNDMakes?src=hash&quot;&gt;#SNDMakes&lt;/a&gt;-Chi &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/E9lWtLgo8n&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/E9lWtLgo8n&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; SND (@SND) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SND/status/696481476708212736&quot;&gt;February 7, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I Want In was built in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.github.com/nicolezhu/playtesting/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, deployed using &lt;a href=&quot;https://iwantingames.herokuapp.com/&quot;&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt;, and our research and demo slides can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1NV5ndEDgpt_2JxhuT4tpmnt8O5G5PCvU8VeOufZ71Dc/pub?slide=id.g831555176_0_277&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. My teammates Charlie and Nicole also wrote great posts about the weekend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blog.codepen.io/2016/02/20/experience-sndmakes-chicago/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.medium.com/learning-journalism-tech/why-you-should-do-sndmakes-45b017f6fd4c#.yz9dr6qbw/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; ✧&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 00:42:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://allysonkate.github.io//work/2016/02/07/SND-Makes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://allysonkate.github.io//work/2016/02/07/SND-Makes/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Big Frame &amp; Youtube</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Youtube_Work.png&quot; alt=&quot;Big Frame&quot; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 2013, I’ve been working with and as talent at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bigfra.me/&quot; title=&quot;Big Frame&quot;&gt;Big Frame&lt;/a&gt;, a multi-channel YouTube network in Los Angeles. Youtube has been a huge part of my life since 2007, which I talk about a little more &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@allysonkate/my-youtube-c07682d16efa#.vrqvjemfp/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. In 2013 I signed with Big Frame for two years as a content creator, producing videos on my personal channel in conjunction with a all-female vertical network initiative. As it became clearer to me that I didn’t want to pursue YouTube as a career, I began fostering a design freelance relationship with Big Frame (now owned by DreamWorks/AwesomenessTV), which has now grown beyond my contract as talent. ✧&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few of the YouTubers I’ve worked with include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sarah Penna &lt;em&gt;(Big Frame co-founder, now with AwesomenessTV)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Joe Penna &lt;em&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/MysteryGuitarMan/&quot; title=&quot;MysteryGuitarMan&quot;&gt;MysteryGuitarMan&lt;/a&gt; → 2.85 mil)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jimmy Tatro &lt;em&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/lifeaccordingtojimmy/&quot; title=&quot;LifeAccordingToJimmy&quot;&gt;LifeAccordingToJimmy&lt;/a&gt; → 2.5 mil)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rebecca Black &lt;em&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/rebecca/&quot; title=&quot;rebecca&quot;&gt;rebecca&lt;/a&gt; → 1.25 mil)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jenn McAllister &lt;em&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/jennxpenn/&quot; title=&quot;jennxpenn&quot;&gt;jennxpenn&lt;/a&gt; → 2.25 mil)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arden Rose &lt;em&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/ARose186/&quot; title=&quot;rebecca&quot;&gt;ARose186&lt;/a&gt;  → 1.3 mil)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 23:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://allysonkate.github.io//work/2015/11/14/big-frame3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://allysonkate.github.io//work/2015/11/14/big-frame3/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>She Hacks Tumblr</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I had the privilege of attending an all female hackathon at Cleverbridge in Chicago focused on the goal of getting more young girls interested in STEM. My group set out to build a beginner-friendly playground that teaches young girls how to customize their Tumblr theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Tumblr remains the only widely used social platform that lets you customize the code, unlike years ago when many of us became familiar with code by customizing Neopets or Myspace layouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there it was. We had our passion product. We were going to build not just a tutorial, but a Tumblr playground. A low-steaks environment to learn, mess up, add personality, and instantly see the effects of &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; code on &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the generous social reach of one of our group members, we were able to do some quick field research regarding interest in the product and features they’d like to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AnnaRussett&quot;&gt;@AnnaRussett&lt;/a&gt; yes &amp;amp; no :/ im still learning how to code&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; toni-gayle (@dumbchie) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dumbchie/status/655177118494687232&quot;&gt;October 17, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AnnaRussett&quot;&gt;@AnnaRussett&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;#39;ve copy and pasted themes but I&amp;#39;ve never made my own it seems too hard 😂&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Lil-E (@lelilliann) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lelilliann/status/655176946972798980&quot;&gt;October 17, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AnnaRussett&quot;&gt;@AnnaRussett&lt;/a&gt; music!! I don&amp;#39;t know how to put a player on there.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; kris (@kristenlongg) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kristenlongg/status/655185262553657344&quot;&gt;October 17, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/SheHacks_Screens.png&quot; alt=&quot;She Hacks Tumblr&quot; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Together, we spent our Saturday creating She Hacks Tumblr.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Built using HTML, CSS, and Javascript, our team built a bare bones Tumblr theme using minimal code. The interface features two interactive drawers, one with the step by step instructions and definitions and one where the user writes the code, which is then reflected on the page in real time. I was responsible for the UI &amp;amp; UX and partnered up for the HTML &amp;amp; CSS. The biggest challenge during any hackathon is always time, but we were able to develop the first few tutorial steps and push live for the demo on &lt;a href=&quot;http://shehacks.tumblr.com/&quot; title=&quot;She Hacks Tumblr&quot;&gt;shehacks.tumblr.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/QuitAward.png&quot; alt=&quot;quit award&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;After 8 hours of coding, we presented in front of a panel of judges and won the “Quit Your Day Job” Award. Although we do plan on developing the product further, I can’t say any of us have taken that award literally yet.&lt;/em&gt; ✧&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 01:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://allysonkate.github.io//work/2015/10/31/she-hacks-tumblr/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://allysonkate.github.io//work/2015/10/31/she-hacks-tumblr/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don&#39;t Read The Ipsum</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Ipsum1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Comedy Hack Day&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2015 I had the absolute pleasure to be accepted to participate in Chicago’s first &lt;a href=&quot;http://comedyhackday.com&quot; title=&quot;Comedy Hack Day&quot;&gt;Comedy Hack Day&lt;/a&gt;, a hackathon started by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cultivatedwit.com/&quot; title=&quot;Cultivated Wit&quot;&gt;Cultivated Wit&lt;/a&gt; in SF. By far one of the most incredible weekends of my year. I laughed and learned an incredible amount with our diverse group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Ipsum_Click.png&quot; alt=&quot;Comedy Hack Day&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our million dollar idea? Don’t Read The Ipsum. We created a web app that generates artisan jumbled words based on Reddit threads, Twitter handles, and New York Times article searches, for a much more enjoyable Lorum Ipsum experience. I was responsible for the UI &amp;amp; UX and partnered up for the HTML &amp;amp; CSS. After presenting in front of a panel of judges, we ended up a finalist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.comedyhackday.org/demosmade/2015/10/5/dont-read-the-ipsum/&quot;&gt;Read more about it&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://ipsum.click&quot;&gt;try it out yourself.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Logo and illustrations: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kalehummus&quot;&gt;Subi Shah&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 01:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://allysonkate.github.io//work/2015/10/02/ipsum-click/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://allysonkate.github.io//work/2015/10/02/ipsum-click/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Echo Magazine</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the spring of 2013 I served as Art Director over a team of 30 designers and writers for the Summer/Fall 2013 issue circulating 30,000 copies in the Greater Chicago area. See the full edition &lt;a href=&quot;https://issuu.com/echomag/docs/echomagfall13&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/echocover.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cover&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hiddentruths1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;page 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hiddentruths2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;page 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 01:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://allysonkate.github.io//work/2015/10/02/echo/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://allysonkate.github.io//work/2015/10/02/echo/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
